https://ossory.ie/diocese/diocesan-office/data-privacy-notice/

PARISH COLLECTION
€ Donation Amount:
€5.00€10.00€25.00€50.00Custom Amount
Donate Now
DIOCESAN COLLECTION
Diocesan Collections
€ Donation Amount:
€5.00€10.00€25.00€50.00Custom Amount
Donate Now
Data Privacy Notice
Diocese of Ossory Privacy Statement
The Diocese of Ossory fully respects your right to privacy and your personal data will be treated with the highest standards of security and confidentiality, in accordance with the Data Protection Acts 1998, 2003 and the Data Protection Regulations (GDPR) 2018.  For the purposes of GDPR, the Data Controller for the Diocese, is the Bishop of Ossory, located at the Diocesan Office, James’ Street, Kilkenny. For information held in the parishes, the Parish Priest/Administrator is the Data Controller.
This Privacy Statement explains how we process personal information, in particular the data that we receive about you.
What Information we collect about you?
The Diocese of Ossory receives personal data about you in various ways, including directly from the individual, family members, other parishioners, other dioceses, schools, groups you are involved in, employers, revenue, charities, medical professionals, cctv and web cameras, An Garda Siochana, social services and other law enforcement bodies. The personal data that is collected may include;
Information about the Sacraments of Baptism, Holy Communion, Confirmation and Marriage and Ordinations.
Information in relation to donations to a parish, certain information about you will be shared with the Diocese under the requirements of the Charities Act or to claim tax rebates on donations.
Safeguarding information as required by the National Safeguarding Office.
Information gathered for the furtherance of faith development services and supports.
Depending on the particular circumstances, we may collect and hold a range of different information about you. This may include name, address, phone number, age, date of birth, e-mail address, family status, nationality, PPS number (where authorised by law), financial information (such as bank details), employment data and qualifications, information about your current involvement with the diocese, information on volunteers, cctv recordings and photographs.
Special category information such as that which reveals your religious beliefs may also be collected and processed.
We may also hold information as a result of background checks for volunteers.
This list is not exhaustive.
Processing of personal information and the lawful bases for processing your data?
Personal Information may be collected in a number of ways including face to face meetings, e-mail, by phone and by forms sent to the Diocesan office. There are six lawful bases by which we can hold your personal data;
Consent:You have given consent to process your data and consent can be withdrawn at any time.
Legitimate Interest:This includes any activities that involve advancing and maintaining the Roman Catholic Religion, providing information about the activities of the diocese, raising charitable funds etc.
Contract:If you have a contract with an individual and in order to fulfil the contract you need to process their personal data.
Legal Obligation: Processing of data is necessary to comply with a legal obligation
Public Interest: Processing of data is necessary to carry out a task in the public interest
Vital Interest: Processing of data is necessary to protect your vital interest.
What do we use the Information for?
To celebrate baptisms, confirmations, marriages, ordinations and funerals and for general pastoral and spiritual care
To provide information that you request from us
To process various application forms
For tax or donation requests
Communication in relation diocesan events
To process job applications
Dealing with complaints and enquiries
To administer, support, improve and develop the administration of the Diocese’s work and operations and to keep the Diocese’s accounts and records up to date
For auditing and statistical purposes
As required by any law applicable to us or arising from your interaction with us
Technical details in connection with number of visits to the Diocesan website and may be logged on the Diocesan Server
CCTV recordings for security purposes and to help create a safer environment for the clergy members, staff, parishioners, volunteers and visitors.
In the case of web cameras, to stream mass to allow those who are unable to attend the opportunity to watch the service.
The Diocese of Ossory does not use automatic decision- making software and does not engage in profiling.
How and whom do we share your information?
The information that you provide to the Diocese of Ossory is only used in accordance with the purpose for which you provide the information and with your consent. This information will only be retained for as long as required and for the purposes for which it was gathered.
Information may be shared with statutory or church bodies for tax relief purposes or law enforcement agencies for the prevention and detection of crime.
Information may be only shared with third parties who assist us with our work.
Information where permitted by law or to meet a legal obligation, we reserve the right to release personal data without your consent and or with/without consulting you.
Where is your information stored?
We store your information in hard copy or electronic format, in storage facilities that we own and operate ourselves or that are owned and operated by our service providers.
How long is your information retained?
Your information is retained for as long as is necessary with regard to the purpose for which it was collected or lawfully processed or for as long as necessary in light of our legal obligations.
How is your information kept safe and accurate?
The Diocese of Ossory is committed to keeping your information safe and secure. To prevent unauthorised access or disclosure, a number of suitable physical and electronic procedures are in place to safeguard your data. The Diocese has technical and organisational security measures in place to protect your data from accidental or intentional manipulation, loss, destruction or access by unauthorised persons. We constantly review our security measures in line with technological advances.
We seek to ensure that your personal data is accurate and up to date. However, you are responsible for informing us of any changes to your personal data and other information.
No personal identifiable information is collected on our website from people who browse the site.
If you wish to obtain any data stored about you, you can make a written request by filling out a Subject Access Request Form. Forms can be obtained by contacting the Ossory Diocesan Office, James’ Street, Kilkenny, tel. 056-7762448 or e-mail admin@ossory.ie
What are your rights?
Under the GDPR, you have the right to request access to the personal information held about you. Any requests should be addressed to the Diocesan Office (contact details above). Requests will be dealt with, within 30 days of receipt, unless there is a reason for the delay, which is justifiable.
You have the following rights;
Right of Access– You have the right to access information we hold about you.
Right of Correction– You have the right to correct information that is inaccurate or incomplete.
Right of Erasure– In certain circumstances you can ask for data that we hold about you to be erased i.e. the right to be forgotten.
Right to Restriction of Processing– Where certain conditions apply, you have the right to restrict processing of your personal data
Right of Portability– Subject to certain circumstances, you have the right to have any data that we hold about you transferred to another organisation where we hold it in electronic form.
Right to Object– You have the right to object to certain types of processing of data.
The Right to lodge a complaintwith the Data Protection Commissioner’s Office.
Cookies and web analytics
We use Google Analytics to track user engagement and usage on our website. The cookies allow us to understand the traffic to our website e.g. number of visits and time spent on the site. This process does collect data, but in an anonymous form and this information helps us to develop the website and enhance the user experience. For further information on Google’s Privacy Policy and Google Analytics please visit the following links (https://www.google.com/policies/privacy)and for Google Analytics by visiting the following link (https:// support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en)
Review and amendment of our privacy statement
This privacy statement explains the privacy policy for the Diocese of Ossory. The diocese reserves the right to review and amend this statement at any time without notice.
Further information and contact details
To exercise any relevant rights, queries or complaints or make a subject access request please contact the Ossory Diocesan Office, James’ Street, Kilkenny, tel. 056-7762448 or e-mail admin@ossory.ie
You may also contact the Data Protection Commissioner Office on 00-353-57-8684800 or Lo-call 1890-252-231 or by e-mail info@dataprotection.ieor by Post to; Data Protection Commissioner, Canal House, Station Road, Portarlington R32 AP23 Co. Laois or the Dublin Office, 21 Fitzwilliam Square, Dublin 2 D02 RD28.
Click here to download Diocese of Ossory Privacy Statement
Ossory Diocesan OfficeCharity Reg No: 20015831
James’s Street, Kilkenny
Tel: 056-7762448
Fax: 056-7763753
E-mail: bishop@ossory.ie
© 2009 - 2020 Ossory Diocese – Designed and Developed by GetOnline ProData Privacy Notice
We use cookies in our website to give you the most relevant experience by remembering your preferences and repeat visits. By clicking “Accept”, you consent to the use of the cookies explicitly. Visit Cookie Settings to know more about the cookies used on our website. View cookie policy: Cookie PolicyNecessaryNon NecessaryUncategorizedAnalyticsPerformancePreferencesAdvertisementCookie settingsACCEPTPrivacy & Cookies Policy
Close
Privacy Overview
This website uses cookies to improve your experience while you navigate through the website. Out of these cookies, the cookies that are categorized as necessary are stored on your browser as they are essential for the working of basic functionalities of the website. We also use third-party cookies that help us analyze and understand how you use this website. These cookies will be stored in your browser only with your consent. You also have the option to opt-out of these cookies. But opting out of some of these cookies may have an effect on your browsing experience.
Necessary
Always Enabled
Necessary cookies are absolutely essential for the website to function properly. This category only includes cookies that ensures basic functionalities and security features of the website. These cookies do not store any personal information.
Non Necessary
Any cookies that may not be particularly necessary for the website to function and is used specifically to collect user personal data via analytics, ads, other embedded contents are termed as non-necessary cookies. It is mandatory to procure user consent prior to running these cookies on your website.
Uncategorized
Undefined cookies are those that are being analyzed and have not been classified into a category as yet.
Analytics
Analytical cookies are used to understand how visitors interact with the website. These cookies help provide information on metrics the number of visitors, bounce rate, traffic source, etc.
Performance
Performance cookies are used to understand and analyze the key performance indexes of the website which helps in delivering a better user experience for the visitors.
Preferences
Preference cookies are used to store user preferences to provide content that is customized and convenient for the users, like the language of the website or the location of the visitor.
Advertisement
Advertisement cookies are used to provide visitors with relevant ads and marketing campaigns. These cookies track visitors across websites and collect information to provide customized ads.
[ Placeholder content for popup link ]
WordPress Download Manager - Best Download Management Plugin
Close
